ILGWU. Canadian Area films, 5780/038 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Canadian Area films
1958-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5780/038 AV
8.67 cubic feet
8.7 linear feet
Film, reel-to-reel audio tape.
Films generated and collected by Canadian locals of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5489880
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
August 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, August 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Scope and Contents
Films generated and collected by Canadian locals of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
General
"Permanent deposit".
Women's clothing industry--Canada.; Women's clothing industry--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--Canada.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--Canada.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--Canada.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5489880
- 1. Luigi Infantino 2. Paolo Lipiari 3. Michelo Argento. Union film. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Italien; Copie; Dactylographie
- 1. Damato Giorgio. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Original
- 1. Anuntiat Adresso 2. Lumia-Maria 3. Dipaula-Anne 4. Carmena de Santos 5. Tissera-Niro 6. Rossetta-Elsini 7. Ginseno-Sel. De Oso. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Italien copie
- M. Poirier. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Copie; Dactylographie; Anglais; Francais; Syncro
- M. Tony Tueci. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 5)
- M. Tony Tueci. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Copie
- Guisepe Anania; Dierriere entrevue (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1. Giovanni-D'Alesio 2. Enta-Janiello 3. Maria-Motta. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Copie; Dactylographie
- Frances Fioramore. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Italien. Original
- Immaculata Coppiello (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Giovanni-D'Alesio. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1. Luigi Infantino, 2. Paolo Lipari, 3. Michelo Argento. Reel II., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Sept. 28; Original
- 1. Enta Janiello, 2. Maria Motta. Union Film, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1. Angela-Marino, 2. Damato-Giorgio. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Italien. Copie. Dactylogrphie
- 1. Amadeo-Lumia., 2. Natalima-Bartolini, 3. Antonio-Caso. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Italien. Copie. Dactylographie.
- 1. Mr. Bresner. Union Fil. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  English. Original #3 (Non sync)
- 1. Anuntiat Adresso, 2. Lumia-Maria, 3. Dipaula-Anne, 4. Carmena de Santos, 5. Tissera-Niro. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Pietro Antonelli, Giuseppe Anania. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Copie. Dactylographie.
- 1. Francesco-Fioramore, 2. Immaculata-Coppiel. (CONE) Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Italien. Dactylographie.
- Pietro Antonelli. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 1. Loisita Figini, 2. Giusefina Del Gesso. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Roland Poirier. Union Film. Reel 1. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Copie 3 ¾
- Harry Titeman II (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Miss Charpentierr, reel 1, Prises 1-5. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- M. Myer Berlin (Box 1, Folder 25)
- 1. H. Titleman, 2. Albert-Eaton. Union Film (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Anglais. Copie. Dactylographie
- Mrs. Whitehead (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Copie 3 3/4 " de l'original #1. Dactylographie
- R. Messier (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Sonseul pour transfer. E.U
- Offices sounds. Wild Trk. Union [Film] (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Music Trk. Union Film. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Pour transfer
- Marielle Moore (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Ambiance and sonseul Anglais. Pour transfer
- Therese Phaneuf (?)/Grievance Committee (Box 1a, Folder 32)
  Son seul Anglais pour transfer
- Comite du Greive (Box 1a, Folder 33)
  Italian. Son seul transfer
- Bresner (Box 1a, Folder 34)
  Son seul pour transfer
- [Correspondence relating to film], 1970-1971 (Box 1a, Folder 35)
- [Text relating to film] (Box 1a, Folder 36)
- Mr. Bresner; Union Film #2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  English; Non Sync; Original
- Roland Poirier. Union Film. #1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Copie 3 ¾" Francais; acetate
- Mrs Whitehead (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Original #1; acetate
- M. Silverman (exc-humor) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Original 7 ½
- Discour-Anglais. Mrs. Bresner. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Original; 7.5 NAB, Son, Reel No. 3, triacetate
- Aurore La Pierre, Bob Seul (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Union Film. Original. Acetate
- Anita Marleau (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Francais. Union Film. Copie. 3 ¾ #1; Reel #3, dactylographie
- Miss Charpentier (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Union Film. Copie of Original. 3 ¾ Reel #1 Dactylographie; acetate
- Sam Kibrick. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Original; 7 ½
- Shildkraut (Sans filtre) Abe Rudy (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Original 7 ½; acetate
- Mr. Meakins (English) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Copie 3 ¾" Union Film. Dactylographie. Reel 1 at 2.
- Avec Marielle Moore #2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Union Film Bob #2 Original; acetate
- Racine material (Box 2, Folder 13)
  English, French, and Italian
- Y. Charpentier I (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Y. Charpentier II (Box 2, Folder 15)
- M. Myer Berline; Shildkraut (sans filter); Abe Rudy (Box 2, Folder 16)
  dactylographie 7 ½ copies; acetate
- Max Share (Box 2, Folder 17)
  7 ½ Original; acetate
- Mlle. Aurore La Pierre (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Copie de l'original; 3 ¾ Union Film; Bob 1; Dactylographie
- B. Shane I (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Morris-Feilgelson (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Bob 1 at 2; Copie 3 ¾ ;Anglais; Union Film; Dactylographie #1; acetate
- Mr. Bresner (English) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  (Sync) Original Union Film #1; triacetate
- Marielle Moore (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Union Film; Original #1; Bob #1; acetate
- Mlle. Lilian Monohan, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Sept. 10; #2 7 ½ IPS Original
- Mlle. Lilian Monohan; Bobine, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Sept. 10; 7 ½ IPS Original
- Mme. Pauline Lamothe Di Stefano (Box 2, Folder 25)
  1/3 7 ½ Original
- M. Messier; Mlle Chapagne (Box 2, Folder 26)
  1F4 English and French; 6F5 1-2-3-4 ;Copie 3 ¾
- 1. Mr. Myer-Berlin, 2. Kibrick (Sam), 3. Max-Share (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Union Film. Copie. Anglais. 3 ¾ Dactylographie
- Therese Pheuneuf (Box 2, Folder 28)
  few minutes French, then English; 3 ¾ copy; union flim reel; #1 dactylographie; acetate
- M. Liberman Original (English) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Union Films Non-synch Reel 2
- M. Liberman Copie (English) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Union Films; Reel 1-8; Dactylographie; acetate
- 1. Luigi Infantino, 2. Paolo Lipari, 3. Michelo Argento, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Sept. 28; Unione Filmo; Original 1
- Romeo Vezima (san filter) II (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Leona Jodoin Original (by phone) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Union film; Bob #2; acetate
- 1. Natalina-Bartolini 2. Antonio-Caso, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Sept. 29; Union Film; Italien; Original; acetate
- Miss Charpentier; Original (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Union Film (English); Reel #1; acetate
- Bob I Union ([illegible] cheques) (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Aldea Guillermette (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Frank Fioramore (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Washington #4 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  B-2 H+2 28+4
- "Sod turning, Plateau St" (Box 2, Folder 40)
  polyester
- M. Silverman; Max Share (Box 3, Folder 1)
  7 ½ copie dacytlographi; acetate
- Mr. Meyer Berlin (Box 3, Folder 2)
  331 E, Reel #1; Union Film; 7 ½ original
- Mde. Aurore LaPierre [illegible]; M.A. Carrier; Ambiance (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Bob I' 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Soir ambiance manufacture; Mariana B. Italian; Angela de Paula 57; Emilio 60, Bartolini 34; Theresa 59; [illegible] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  S.U.P. transfer; acetate
- Albert Eaton I and II (Box 3, Folder 5)
  teste déjà dactylographic 7 ½; (sans filter); acetate
- Mr. Silverman, 681E; Miss Charpentier Bob 1 – Prises 1-5, 2F-10; Miss Charpentier, Bob 2 – Prises 6-9, 2F-10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Union film 3 ¾ IPS (copies); triacetate
- Morris Feigelson, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Oct. 26; Bob II Union; 91-E (sync)
- Flore Plante (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Bob #; Original Union Film
- Aldea Guillemette; Mme Pauline Lamothe Di Stefano (Box 3, Folder 9)
  1/23; 7 ½ copie; dactylographie
- Mr. Liberman (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Synch; English; Union Film; Reel #1
- Morris Feigelson 91-E, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Oct. 26; Bob III Union; (no sync)
- M. Libberman (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Original (English); Union films; Nonsynch Reel #4 (actually #1 in order)
- Maiorino 59.2; Capiello 30; Gina 95; Ambiance Manufacture Minicucci 62.1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  7 ½ NAB original
- Mlle Charpentier 52-53-54 sans filter, narratrice 23-24-25 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  acetate
- Mme. Guilemette 7-8-9-10-11-11 (prises 11 la deuxieme est la bonne)-12-13-14-15-16-17 (illegible) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Prises 45-46-47-48-49-50-51-52-53 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  sync version; italienne; Bon; Bob 4; acetate
- Anglais M. Poirier (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Original; Union Film; syncro; 2 pour transfer; synch seul; acetate
- M. Manel (sync) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  original; reel #1; union film; acetate
- Mme. Moore 4F8, 6F7, 7F5 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  mostly French, some English interview; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Marielle Moore (Box 3, Folder 20)
  sound alone; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Mr. Liberman (Box 3, Folder 21)
  (English) Union film; copie 3 ¾ dactylographie; reel 3 and 4; acetate
- M. Harry Titeman I (Box 3, Folder 22)
  original 7 ½; acetate
- Flore plante (Box 3, Folder 23)
  union film; original Bob #1; copie #1 3 3 ¾ " dactylographie; acetate
- M. Paolo Picari; M. Lipari; Frank Fiaramore; Anita Greeberg (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Italien; 7 /12 NAB original; acetate
- Frank Fioramore; Sam Kibrick (Box 3, Folder 25)
  3 ¾ déjà dactylographie copie
- Olga Kolesar (Box 3, Folder 26)
  V.O [voiceover?]; Anglais (sync); 7 ½ IPS
- Enza Ianiello 63; Si Bresne 36r; Asunta Clement 46; Ambiance Manufacture a desso 61 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  7 ½ NAB originale; Italien; acetate
- 61E and 71E and 151E Kibrick (Sam); Max Share (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Union films; reel #1; 7 ½ original; acetate
- Mlle Carpentier 30-31-32-33; Me Guillemette 1-2-3-4-5-6 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Fiaramore IT 23; 23/3 Luigi Antonini; Mme. Di Stefano 1-2; M. LeClerc 1-2-3 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Charpentier I and II (Box 3, Folder 31)
  7 ½ tento dactylographie copie; acetate
- 1. Mr. Shane, 2. Discour Cicconstance, 3. Mlle Charpentier; Banquet (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Charpentier Suite; dactylographie
- 1. Remise-cheques; 2. Discour-Shane (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Union Film; Copie; dactylographie
- Medical clinic; reel #3 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Union film; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Albert Eaton II (sans filter) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  original 7 ½; MP#50; acetate
- Miss Charpentier prises 1-5; M. Poirier (Box 3, Folder 36)
  2F10 copie, 3 ¾,
- M. Poirier (Box 3a, Folder 37)
  Union Film; Fracais Syncro; acetate
- Leona Jodoin (Box 3a, Folder 38)
  Original (by phone); Union Film; Bob #1; acetate
- Mrs. Champagne (Box 3a, Folder 39)
  611E-Takes 1x2x3; union film; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- M. Bastien; M. Biamce cours atisanat; Ambiance (Box 3a, Folder 40)
  Italienne atisanat; Ambiance peinture; 7 ½ NAB Original; acetate
- Aldea Guillemette 3F6 (Box 3a, Folder 41)
  reel #1; 1 minute on reel #2; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Mr. Shane (Box 3a, Folder 42)
  English; last take 701RE; Union films; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- M. Bresner (Box 3a, Folder 43)
  Anglais; Union film 3-4; dactylographie
- M. Bresner (Box 3a, Folder 44)
  copie; Union film 1-2; dactylographie
- Office convseration (Box 3a, Folder 45)
  Francais; Italien Grief Comite 1 et 2 dactylographie
- Grievance committee (Box 3a, Folder 46)
  wild trk
- M. Manel (Box 3a, Folder 47)
  Union film; Anglais; reel 1; copie
- Albert Eaton (Box 3a, Folder 48)
  Union 131E (27-10-70) (200' [illegible] no sync) (sync)
- Anne Marie, Doi Ron [?], 4B1 (Box 3a, Folder 49)
- Mr. S. Bresner (Box 3a, Folder 50)
  English; last take 371E; French 7F2 commence 2F2; union film; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Prises 11-12-13-14, sync 15-16-17-18-19-20-21-22-23-24-25-26-27 (Box 3a, Folder 51)
  version italienne; acetate
- Prises 1-2-3-4-5-6-7-8-9 (Box 3a, Folder 52)
  sync; version italienne; acetate
- Discours Shanve Mai, 1968 (Box 3a, Folder 53)
- Paul Noel (Box 3a, Folder 54)
  3 spectacle union original; acetate
- Ambiance [illegible] (Box 3a, Folder 55)
  Bob 1N5 (2); 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- J.J. Spector; interview 37 strike (Box 3a, Folder 56)
  15 speed—sound only; Les Midinettes; original #1; acetate
- Aldea Guillemette 3F6; M. Roland Poirier 3F5-4F8-51E; Mme. Aurore Lapierre Ma Carrier (Box 3a, Folder 57)
  copie 3 ¾; acetate
- B. Shane II (original) (Box 3a, Folder 58)
- Prises 28-29-30-31-32-33-34-35-36-37-38-39-40-41-42-43-44 (Box 3a, Folder 59)
- Banquet M. Chane [?]; T. Casgran [?]; Dublde [?]; [illegible] (Box 3a, Folder 60)
  7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- M. La Raselle [?]; M. Roland Poirier 3F5, 4F8, 251E 400 (Box 3a, Folder 61)
  7 ½ NAB [illegible]; acetate
- M. Leclerc 4 et 5; Mlle Marliou (Box 3a, Folder 62)
- Mlle Tardiz [?] (Box 3a, Folder 63)
  English; 691 Union films; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Union de Vetement Dames (Box 3a, Folder 64)
  7 ½ NAB Son; Reel #1; triacetate
- Union de Vetement Dames (Box 3a, Folder 65)
  7 ½ NAB Son; Reel #2; triacetate
- Poirier, Rolland (Box 3a, Folder 66)
  original; reel #1; union film; French
- Mr. Rolland Poirier (Box 3a, Folder 67)
  original #2; union film; English; triacetate
- Original Mary Szabo (English) (Box 3a, Folder 68)
  union film; Herbert Ruff, 2/25/66; Triacetate
- French lady (Anita Marleau?) (Box 3b, Folder 69)
  Original Reel #1; Union Film
- Therese Pheneuf (Box 3b, Folder 70)
  original; union film (French little, only reel, mostly in English); acetate
- Highlights of an Address by Harry L. Golden, Editor of The Carolina Israelite, 1958 (Box 3b, Folder 71)
  to the Jewish Labor Committee 3rd National Trade Union Conference on Civil Rights; Subject: A Southerner Looks at Integration; For Steve Perkel [?] from Sid Blum [?]; Includes transcription of Golden address
- [no label] (Box 3b, Folder 72)
- Banquet, Mr. Shane, 1970 (Box 3b, Folder 73)
  November; Tape 1
- Banquet, Mr. Shane, 1970 (Box 3b, Folder 74)
  November; Tape 2 (Side 1: 1 hour, end of banquet, Side 2: blank, not used)
- Banquet, Mr. Shane, 1970 (Box 3b, Folder 75)
  Nov. 15; Radio; TV; (Side 1: 1. Pulse, Channel 6, TV, 2. Hour Glass, Channel 12, TV, 3. CKVL Radio 11/15/70, 4. CFOX Radio, 11/15/70)
- Union (copie) (Box 3b, Folder 76)
  7/5 IPS, final mix Anglais
- B. Shane I, 7 ½; B. Shane II, 7 ½ (Box 4, Folder 1)
  texte déjà dactylogrphie; copie; acetate
- Morris Feigelson, copie, 3 ¾, 91E; Mme. F. Plante; M. Belander (1F5); M. Messier (1F4): #2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- I. M. Harry Titeman; II. Harry Titeman, copie, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  March 17; texte dactylographic; acetate
- Mme. Moore; Vezina, Francais (Box 4, Folder 4)
  4F8, Francais, 6F7, 7F5, copie, 3 ¾; M., 1F8
- Bob I. Union; Edlyn Whitehead, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Oct. 26; 571E (Sync)
- Albert Erton, Edlyn Minitenerd, H. Titleman (Box 4, Folder 6)
  3 ¾ copie; triacetate
- Bob 3- UIOVD [ILGWU] (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Discour Italien (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Original, 7/5 NAB, SON, reel #4; triacetate
- B.6.T [?] Union. Norris Feigelson, Myer Kerkin (Box 4, Folder 9)
  3 ¾ copie
- Mr. Meakins (English) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Original (synch) start, union films, reel 1; 1 part non-sync
- Mlle. Charpentier; union film (French), reel #1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Original; acetate
- Romeo Vezina (sans filter (Box 4, Folder 12)
  7 ½ original; acetate
- 1. Asunta Clemente; 2. Anitta Grenberg, union film (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Italien, original; acetate
- Mme. Lilian Monoman, Bob 1 at 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  dactylographie, 3 ¾ IPS, copie; acetate
- M. Messier 1F4 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  sync et sans seul English and French, union film 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- Mlle. Charpentier (Box 4, Folder 16)
  48-49-50 sans filter-51; acetate
- M. Shane (Box 4, Folder 17)
  chacun de midinettes, 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- M. Spector, prise 1-2; Narratrice 1-2-3; suite sur Bob 2, 4(2°)-5(2°)-6(2°) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Miss Charpentier reel 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  prises 7-8-9, 2F10, copie, 3 ¾; PAS, Carmen
- Veller x Bisaillon, French girls, Mlle Irene Arrelle, union films (Box 4, Folder 20)
  7 ½ NAB, original; acetate
- 1. Asunta Clemente, 2. Anitta Grenberg, union film (Box 4, Folder 21)
  copie, Italien, Dactylographie; acetate
- Mr. Meakings (English); reel 2; union films (Box 4, Folder 22)
  original (non-synch); acetate
- Uinon H. Titleman; reel 1, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Oct. 27; 51E, 7.5
- Narratrice prise 7; narratrice 8-9-10-11; Charpentier prise 1-2-3-2-3, prise 4-5-6-7-8-9-10 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  la derniere est la bonne; la premiere de 11 est la bonne; acetate
- Mlle Charpentier 44-45-46-47; Mme. Humbeault 1 [illegible] 2; les 2 femmes 1-2 il y a 2 prises 2-4-5-6 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- M. Vesina, 1F8; union films (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Francais; 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- J.J. Spector; interview 37 strike (Box 4, Folder 27)
  7/12 speed, sound only; les mideinettes, original #2; acetate
- 4. Spectacle union original (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Mme F. Plante, M. Brelander 1F5, M. Messier 1F4 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Elegant Shop (Marielle Moore) 4F5, 4F6, union films (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Mrs. Champagne, Italien 73, prises 1-2-3-4-5-6, union films; fin: resumes local 262 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  7 ½ NAB, original #3; acetate
- M. Luigi Infantino It[alian?]-31-(1:2-3)-2T71, Mrs. Olda Koesar, Eng[lish?] (test), union films (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Infantino, Lipari (Itlalien) 65; Mlle Marleau P.I.B. (Francais), Giovani D'Allessio 95, Anne Marie Doiron 4B0 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Narratrice 16-17-18-19 la derniere; Mlle Charpentier 13-14-15-15-16-17 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Mrs. Irene Courtois, English, 521E, It. 38 Will [?] Libberman Greek, union films (Box 4a, Folder 35)
- Son M. Biance, 9380 St. Laurent; Toni Tucci, Italian; Maria Feranitelli, Italian; Enza Ianiella, Italian scene 63 (Box 4a, Folder 36)
- Albert Eaton I (sans filter) (Box 4a, Folder 37)
- M. Roland Poirier 251 English (Box 4a, Folder 38)
- UIOVD Counseil Executif original (Box 4a, Folder 39)
  MP #58
- Mlle Charpentier 34-35-36-37-38-39-41-42-43-44; de 37-44 vitesse 15; 7 ½ de 34-36 (Box 4a, Folder 40)
- Banquet, M. Shane (Box 4a, Folder 41)
- Bob I union, Morris Feigelson, 1970 (Box 4a, Folder 42)
  Oct. 26; 91-E (no sync)
- Amadeo Lumia; union film (Box 4a, Folder 43)
  Original; Italien; acetate
- 1. Membre du conseil, 2. Mr. Peters et Louis Laberge, banquet, Charpentier (Box 4a, Folder 44)
  copie, Italien, Anglais, dactylographie; acetate
- Mr. Bresner (English); #4 union film (Box 4a, Folder 45)
  (non sync) original; MP# 23; acetate
- Mlle. Charpentier (Box 4a, Folder 46)
  21-22-23-24-25 la derniere-26-27-28-29
- Shane 1st (pas de clap) 2nd sync (Box 4a, Folder 47)
- Mr. Silverman sound sample 681E, union film (Box 4a, Folder 48)
- Manufacture de manteaux, Maria Ceniciose 101 (Box 4a, Folder 49)
  It[alian?] 7 ½ NAB original; acetate
- M. Liberman, original (English), union films non-synch ree #3 (Box 4a, Folder 50)
- Miss Charpentier, reel #3 2F10 takes 6-7-8-9, 2 minutes of reel #2 films (Box 4a, Folder 51)
- Mme Champagne en Francais (Box 4a, Folder 52)
  prises 6F5 1-2-3-4-5 on ambiance, union films, 7 ½ NAB, original; acetate
- Banquet, M. Chane [Shane?], Bressner, Joe Macks, Goldenberg (Box 4a, Folder 53)
- 1 spectacle union (Box 4a, Folder 54)
  syncro original
- Bob 1, Mr. Bresner, Reunion du Comite Executif (Box 4a, Folder 55)
- Bob 1, Mr. Bresner, Reunion du Comite Executif (Box 4a, Folder 55)
  7 ½ NAB, originall acetate
- Mlle Charp[entire] 18, narratrice 20-21-22, Mlle Charpentier 19-20 (Box 4a, Folder 56)
- 1. Mr. Bresner, Mme. Chapagne, 2. Conseil Executif (Box 4a, Folder 57)
  dactylographie, copie; acetate
- Infantino, Lipari 65, locale, [illegible], Sam Liberman, [illegible] (Box 4a, Folder 58)
- Miss Charpentier reel #2, prises 6-7-8-9, 2F10 (plus 2 minutes on reel #3) (Box 4a, Folder 59)
- Miss Charpentier, Anglais 711E, Francais 7F10, Italian 521x2, union filmv (Box 4a, Folder 60)
  7 ½, original
- Mlle Charpentier 11 (2-3)-12, narratrice 10-11 (2)-12 (2), prise 13-14-15 (Box 4a, Folder 61)
- Banquet, M. Chane; MacDonald son seul; MacDonal, syn.; MacKasey son seul Fr.; Stulberg, 2-syn.; Charte, syn (Box 4a, Folder 62)